Inventory of the Francis P. Lee Papers 1727-1866
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Correspondence and Legal Papers.
  - C. E. Gadsden, Charleston, to [Francis P. Lee], August 16, 1845., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:12)
    Professorship [at College of South Carolina?] will probably be abolished; in any case does not think an Episcopalian will be chosen.
  - Charles C. Gaskell, Rose Cottage, Punxsutawney, Pennsylvania, to Francis P. Lee and S[arah] A[nn] C[ooper] Lee, Camden, South Carolina, October 6, 1845., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:13)
    Will send $100; has sold some McKean County land; asks for power of attorney.
  - Sam[ue]l Nicholson, Haddonfield, to Francis P. Lee, October 8, 1845., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:14)
    Accounts for Lee's money in his hand.
  - Sam[ue]l S. Davis, Camden, [South Carolina], to F[rancis] P. Lee, October 20, 1845., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:15)
    Letter of recommendation for professorship at College of South Carolina.
  - R[ichard] W. Howell, Camden, to F[rancis] P. Lee, Camden South Carolina, October 20, 1845., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:16)
    Accounts for Lee's money in his hands; family land deals.
  - Sam[ue]l Nicholson, Philadelphia, to F[rancis] P. Lee, October 24, 1845., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:17)
    Sends money and accounts for Lee's money in his hands.
  - Power of attorney from Francis P. Lee and Sarah A[nn] C[ooper] Lee, October 24, 1845., 3 pages. ADS. Cop. (Box-folder 2:18)
  - Francis P. Lee, Camden, South Carolina to Trustees of South Carolina College, November 1845., 1 page. ACyS. (Box-folder 2:19)
    Applies for position as professor.
  - R[ichard] W. Howell, Camden, to John Wright, Market St., Philad[elphi]a ,November 1, 1845., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:20)
    Will pay debt for Mr. Lee.
  - Promissory note of Rich[ar]d W. Howell, att[orne]y, in fact of Francis P. Lee, to pay Joshua Brick, with attached receipts, November 10, 1845-February 19, 1946., 3 items. (Box-folder 2:20a)
  - R[ichard] W. Howell, Camden, New Jersey, to [Francis P. Lee], November 13, 1845., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:21)
    Morris wants to prosecute Ralph; on family land deals; sends a deed to be executed.
  - B. W. Whilden, Camden, South Carolina, to Francis P. Lee, November 15, 1845., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:22)
  - Sam[ue]l Nicholson, Haddonfield, to Francis P. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, December 8, 1845., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:23)
    Ralph Cooper wants to occupy Francis P. Lee's share of Matlack Farm.
  - W. Morris Cooper, Orchard Hill Farm, Camden County [New Jersey], to "Frank" [Francis P. Lee], Camden, South Carolina, December 8, 1845., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:24)
    On land sales.
  - W. Morris Cooper, Camden County [New Jersey], to "Frank" [Francis P. Lee], Camden, South Carolina, December 23, 1845., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:25)
  - Sam[ue]l Nicholson, Haddonfield, to Francis P. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, December 26, 1845., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:26)
  - [List of parishioners?], [ca. 1846?]., 4 pages. Ms. (Box-folder 2:27)
  - Diagram of pews and prices in Christ Church, Mobile, Alabama, 1846., 1 page. PD. (Box-folder 2:28)
    Francis P. Lee preached there. 2 copies, one with family names written in.
  - List of parishioners, 1846., 6 pages. Ms. (Box-folder 2:29)
  - W. Morris Cooper, Camden County, to Francis P. Lee, South Carolina, January 27, 1846., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:30)
    Discusses selling Matlack Farm; wants to compel Ralph to settle.
  - Charles C. Gaskell, Rose Cottage, to Francis P. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, February 5, 1846., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:31)
    Working on settling B. B. Cooper estate; cannot send money.
  - W. Morris Cooper, Camden County, to Francis P. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, March 10, 1846., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:32)
    Mr. Howell will send $150; wants the deed settled; glad he will visit.
    (On same leaf as Howell to Lee, March 11, 1846.)
  - R[ichard] W. Howell, Camden, New Jersey, to [Francis P. Lee], March 11, 1846., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:32)
    Will send money; will file a bill against Ralph.
    (On same leaf as Cooper to Lee, March 10, 1846.)
  - Rich[ard] W. Howell, Camden, South Carolina, to [Francis P. Lee], March 23, 1846., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:33)
    Sends $150.
  - Francis P. Lee, Columbia, South Carolina, to Sarah C. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, March 30, 1846., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:34)
    "Domestic Journal No. 1." Rode to Columbia.
  - [Francis P. Lee], Tallahassee, Florida, to wife [Sarah C. Lee], Camden, South Carolina, April 1846., 8 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:35)
    Recounts his trip. "Domestic Journal No. 17".
  - Francis P. Lee, Charleston, to Sarah C. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, April 3, 1846., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:36)
    "Domestic Journal 4." Describes his visit; hopes to pay off his bills soon; leaves for Savannah.
  - [Sarah C. Lee], Camden, South Carolina, to Francis P. Lee, Savannah, Georgia, April 4, 1846., 3 pages. AL. (Box-folder 2:37)
    Has been worried about him; Eliza Millar visiting; will not let anyone else read his letters.
  - Sarah [C. Lee], Camden, South Carolina, to Francis P. Lee, Tallahassee, Florida, April 8, 1846., 4 pages. ALS. Fragment. (Box-folder 2:38)
    Visited mother; neighborhood news.
  - Sarah [C. Lee], Camden, South Carolina, to Francis P. Lee, Tallahassee, Florida, April 9, 1846., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:39)
    Received money from Charles Gaskell; neighborhood news; asks about appearance of Fanny's grave.
  - [Francis P. Lee], Savannah, Georgia, to [Sarah C. Lee], April 13, 1846., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:40)
    "Domestic Journal No. 10." He is traveling with Bishop Elliot to Macon; describes his visit; preached on Easter Sunday; is happy staying with his Camden church.
  - Francis P. Lee, Shedville, Tallahassee, Florida, to Sarah C. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, April 20, 1846., 5 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:41)
    "Domestic Journal No. 15." Describes his visit; preached at the capitol; will travel next to Pensacola; Tallahassee has changed much since they lived there.
  - F[rancis] P. Lee, Mobile, Alabama, to Sarah C. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, May 7-8, 1846., 8 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:42)
    Hopes to buy a marble tombstone for Fanny B. Lee; describes his visit to Mobile and the city. "Domestic Journal No. 22."
  - F[rancis] P. L[ee], Mobile, Alabama, to S[arah] C. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, May 11, 1846., 5 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:43)
    "Domestic Journal No. 23." Will take the boat for New Orleans; describes his visit; wants her to ask the vestry to extend his leave of absence.
  - Sarah [C. Lee], Camden, South Carolina, to Francis P. Lee, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, May 13, 1846., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:44)
    Sends neighborhood news; sends copy of letter from Edisto Island church inviting him to be their pastor; advises him to do what he thinks best.
  - W. A. Pratt, et al., Mobile, to Revd. J. A. Massey, n.p., May 14, 1846., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:45)
    Asking that Massey invite [Francis P.] Lee to preach.
  - Jn. Charlund? Mobile, to F[rancis] P. Lee, May 19, 1846., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:46)
    Would like him to preach to the church.
    Also includes draft of Lee's reply, dated May 22, 1846, on same leaf, 1 page. ALS. Cop.
  - F[rancis] P. Lee, New Orleans, to Sarah C. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, May 20, 1846., 7 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:47)
    He is visiting friends; is not looking for a church; is looking for a boat to travel on to Pittsburgh.
  - Francis P. Lee, Steamboat Pacific, Ohio River, to Sarah C. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, May 30, 1846., 8 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:48)
    "Domestic Journal No." Describes his trip from Louisville to Pittsburgh.
  - Reynolds and Co., Charleston, To F[rancis] P. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, June 23, 1846., 1 page. ALS and 2 pages. AD. (Box-folder 2:49)
    His vehicle and harness will arrive at Gadsden on June 27; will send railroad receipt for it. Also includes list of visits to congregation of Grace Church, Camden.
  - Dan[ie]l McNeill, Mobile, to Francis P. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, July 8, 1846., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:50)
    For the wardens and vestry of Christ Church, invites him to be their minister; expects the amended constitution will be adopted. [A copy of the constitution, dated 1835, and proposed amendments, undated, is in Box 1, folder 25.]
  - C. E. Gadsden, C[harles]ton,[South Carolina], to F[rancis] P. Lee, Camden, July 15, 1846., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:51)
    Bishop Gadsden regrets Francis P. Lee leaving; knows little of Edisto or Mobile.
  - , July 27, 1846., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:52)
    Church secretary sends a copy of the resolution of vestry and wardens to accept Francis P. Lee's resignation, passed on July 26.
  - [Francis P. Lee], Camden, South Carolina, to [Daniel McNeill, Mobile, Alabama?], July 25, 1846., 2 pages. AL. (Box-folder 2:52a)
    Current congregation does not want him to leave; vestry has his resignation and should act on it soon; still hopes article in "their [Christ Church, Mobile, Alabama] constitution" will be changed.
  - J. M. Desaussure, Lausanne, to Francis P. Lee, July 27, 1846., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:53)
    Sorry he is leaving.
  - Francis P. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, to "Gentlemen," July 28, 1846., 2 pages. ACyS. (Box-folder 2:54)
    Has decided to accept the pastoral charge of Christ Church, Mobile; asks about a house to rent.
  - Ralph V. M. Cooper, Chews Landing, [New York], to Francis P. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, July 30, 1846., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:55)
    List proceeds from sale [of land?].
  - [Francis P. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, to Vestry, Christ Church, Mobile, Ala.], [July 1846.], 1 page. Df. (Box-folder 2:55a)
    Accepts rectorship of Christ Church, to begin November 15, 1846; objects to the annual election of the rector and hopes they will amend their constitution in that particular, but will serve in any case.
    (On same leaf as draft of letter resigning from Grace Church.)
  - [Francis P. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, to Vestry, Grace Church, Camden, South Carolina], [July 1846.], 1 page. Df. (Box-folder 2:55a)
    Requests permission to resign from the parish; is called to serve in Mobile.
    (On same leaf as draft of letter accepting rectorship of Christ Church.)
  - Jno. McClelland, Camden, South Carolina, to Francis P. Lee, August 1, 1846., 1 page. LS. (Box-folder 2:56)
    Resolutions accepting the resignation of Francis P. Lee as Rector of Grace Church.
  - Dan[ie]l McNeill, Mobile, to Francis P. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, August 6, 1846., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:57)
    Received his acceptance of the ministry; will send information on houses.
  - R[ichard] W. Howell, Camden, New Jersey, to Francis P. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, August 12, 1846., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:58)
    Encloses deeds for land; describes family land deals.
  - Ralph [V. M. Cooper], Chews Landing, [New York], to Francis P. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, August 17, 1846., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:59)
    Describes land sales.
  - Dan[ie]l McNeill, Mobile, to Francis P. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, September 21, 1846., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:60)
    Has secured a house for him.
  - Dan[ie]l McNeill, Mobile, to Francis P. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, October 2, 1846., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:61)
    Got the house on Government Street for him; asks when he will arrive.
  - Rich[ard] W. Howell, to F[rancis] P. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, October 7, 1846., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:62)
    Describes family land transactions; Rev[eren]d Matthews defrocked.
  - W. Morris Cooper, Camden, to "Frank" [Francis P. Lee], October 10, 1846., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:63)
    Sends money; wants to settle land questions.
  - List of communicants of Christ Church, [Mobile, Alabama], November 10, 1846., 4 pages. Ms. (Box-folder 2:64)
    List drawn by J. A. Massey.
  - W. Morris Cooper, Camden, New Jersey, to Francis P. Lee, Mobile, Alabama, November 23, 1846., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:65)
    Also includes R[ichard] W. Howell to Francis P. Lee. Discussion of land sale to Morris.
  - R[ichard] W. Howell, Camden, New Jersey, to [Francis P. Lee], December 1, 1846., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:66)
    Has made out a deed for Mrs. Lee to sign.
  - Folder 67 does not exist in this collection. (Box-folder 2:67)
  - Richard W. Howell to Mrs. [Sarah Ann Cooper] Lee, 1847-1858., 11 items. ALS. (Box-folder 2:68)
    Concerning legal and business matters which Howell managed for Lee.
  - Paul Chapin, Charleston, to Fra[nci]s P. Lee, Mobile, January 18, 1847., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:69)
    Letter of introduction for the Revd. Mr. Williamson.
  - R[ichard] W. Howell, Camden, to [Francis P. Lee], February 3, 1847., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:70)
    Discusses sale of farm.
  - Francis P. Lee, Mobile, Alabama, to R[ichard] W. Howell, Camden, New Jersey, February 8, 1847., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:71)
    Discusses business, sale of Matlack Farm.
  - N. H. Cobbs, Tuscaloosa, to F[rancis] P. Lee, Mobile, Alabama, February 15, 1847., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:72)
    [Bishop] Cobbs will visit Francis P. Lee's church and administer confirmation.
  - Ralph V. M. Cooper, Chews Landing, [New York], to Francis P. Lee, Mobile, Alabama, February 19, 1847., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:73)
    Describes his business affairs.
  - Ralph V. M. Cooper to Francis P. Lee, Mobile, Alabama, February 20, 1847., 1 page. ADS. (Box-folder 2:74)
    Promissory note to buy out the Lees' one-third share in Matlack Farm.
  - Benj[amin] W. Cooper, Camden, to [Francis P. Lee], February 26, 1847., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:74)
    Discusses family business deals.
    (On same leaf as promissory note from Ralph V. M. Cooper and letter from Howell to Lee.)
  - [Richard W. Howell to Francis P. Lee], [ca. February 1847]., 1 page. L. (Box-folder 2:74)
    Discusses Ralph V. M. Cooper's actions on family business deals.
    (On same leaf as promissory note from Ralph V. M. Cooper and letter from Benjamin Cooper to Lee.)
  - Francis P. Lee, Mobile, Alabama, to Sarah C. Lee, New Orleans, Louisiana, March 20, 1847., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:75)
    Describes how he spent his day.
  - [Sarah A. C. Lee?], Camden, South Carolina, to Benjamin W. Cooper, March 22, 1847., 2 pages. AL. Fragment. (Box-folder 2:76)
    Discusses financial problems.
  - Francis P. Lee, Mobile, Alabama, to Sarah C. Lee, New Orleans, Louisiana, March 25, 1847., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:77)
  - W[illia]m M. Garrow, et al., Mobile, to Francis P. Lee, Mobile, April 19, 1847., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:78)
    The vestry and wardens of Christ Church, Mobile, elect F[rancis] P. Lee minister.
  - Receipt of Henry A. Tayloe, Treasurer, Tuscaloosa, [Alabama], for $500 received from Christ Church, Mobile, [Alabama], for the Bishop's salary, May 6, 1847., 1 page. ADS. (Box-folder 2:78a)
  - [Francis P. Lee], Tuscaloosa, to 'wife', May 7, 1847., 4 pages. AL. (Box-folder 2:79)
    Describes his travels.
  - John Wright, Phila[delphia], to R[ichard] W. Howell, Camden, New Jersey, June 4, 1847., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:80)
    Question of collateral for Ralph's loan being returned.
  - Francis P. Lee, Mobile, to R[ichard] W. Howell, Camden, New Jersey, July 1847?, 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:81)
    Has been very busy.
  - Dan[ie]l McNeill, Mobile, to F[rancis] P. Lee, August 20, 1847., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:82)
    He is worried about gossip Mr. Miller is spreading.
  - Margaret R. Deas, Allenwood, to Mrs. [Sarah A. Cooper] Lee, Government Street, [Mobile, Alabama], September 11, 1847., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:82a)
    Glad Mr. Lee is better.
  - Resolution of the wardens and vestry of Christ Church, Mobile, on the death of F[rancis] P. Lee, September 11, 1847., 1 page. ADS. (Box-folder 2:83)
  - Sympathy letters at death of Francis P. Lee, September 14-November 16, 1847., 14 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 2:83a)
  - Sarah A. C. Lee petition to court for letters of administration, September 24, 1847., 4 pages. ADS. (Box-folder 2:84)
  - Benj[amin] W. Cooper account with Sarah A. C. Lee, September 25, 1847., 1 page. D. (Box-folder 2:85)
  - "E," to his sister, Sarah [Ann Cooper Lee], September 1847., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:85a)
    Condolence letter concerning the death [of her husband?]; family news; wishes she would come home.
  - Resolution of Trinity Church, Camden, New Jersey? on death of Francis P. Lee, sent to Mrs. Lee, ca. September 1847., 1 page. DS. (Box-folder 2:85b)
  - Bill and receipts for items bought of S. H. St. John and Co., October 1, 1847., 1 page. DS. (Box-folder 2:86)
  - Account of sales of furniture of Mrs. Lee, sold by Charles T. Stickney, Mobile, October 28, 1847., 2 pages. ADS. (Box-folder 2:87)
  - Accounts for estate of Francis P. Lee, October 1, 1847-May 1, 1849., 2 pages. D. (Box-folder 2:88)
  - Account of estate of Francis P. Lee, October 11-November 4, 1847., 1 page. D. (Box-folder 2:89)
  - Sarah A. C. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, to Richard W. Howell, November 3, 1847., 1 page. ACyS. (Box-folder 2:90)
    Asks him for information on her New Jersey lands and debts.
  - Tho[ma]s Lesesne, Mobile, to Mrs. F[rancis] P. Lee, Camden, So[uth] Carolina,November 10, 1847., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:91)
    Has forwarded her packages.
  - O. J. Hamlin to C. C. Gaskell and Sarah A. C. Lee, 1848-1850., 3 items. ALS. (Box-folder 2:92)
    Discuss selling some of Sarah A. C. Lee's land in Pennsylvania.
  - Documents with regard to Sarah C. Lee being given letters of administration for estate of Francis P. Lee in New Jersey, March 13, 1848., 4 pages. ADS. (Box-folder 2:93)
    Letters granted April 26, 1848.
  - Copy of inventory of estate of Francis P. Lee as presented to Camden County [New Jersey] Surrogate Court, May 1848., 1 page. ADS. (Box-folder 2:94)
  - [Sarah C. Lee], Moorestown, New Jersey, to Charles C. Gaskell, June 29, 1848., 1 page. AL. (Box-folder 2:95)
    Morris purchased her interest in Matlack Farm.
  - Charles C. Gaskell, Rose Cottage, to "cousin" S[arah] A. C. Lee, July 6, 1848., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:96)
    Will send $434.
  - Dan[ie]l McNeill, Mobile, to Sarah C. Lee, Camden, New Jersey, August 9, 1848., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:97)
    Has sent a check to Thomas B. Lee.
  - C[harles] C. Gaskell to "cousin" [Sarah A. C. Lee], 1849., 3 items. ALS. (Box-folder 2:98)
    These letters largely concern business matters which Gaskell managed for Lee.
  - W. Morris Cooper, Moorestown, to "sister" Sarah A. C. Lee, January 18, 1849., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:99)
    On family business deals.
  - Sarah A. C. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, to Charles C. Gaskell, May 31, 1849., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:100)
    Has directed Mr. Vanderkemp to deed land to Gaskell; Francis P. Lee left $4000 in property in Alabama; plans to appoint Mr. Desaussure as guardian for her children's property in Alabama.
  - [Sarah A. C. Lee], Camden, South Carolina, to Richard W. Howell ,October 10, 1849., 2 pages. AL. Fragment. (Box-folder 2:101)
    Informs him of the state of some business affairs; does not like the way C[harles] C. Gaskell is handling her business.
  - Sarah A. C. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, to Richard W. Howell, November 24, 1849., 2 pages. AL. Fragment. (Box-folder 2:102)
    Gives Richard W. Howell instructions on business affairs.
  - C[harles] C. Gaskell to "cousin" Sarah A. C. Lee, 1850., 2 items. ALS. (Box-folder 2:103)
    These letters are largely concerned with business affairs which Gaskell managed for Lee.
  - Tho[ma]s B. Lee, New Orleans, to Sarah [C. Lee], 1850., 13 items. ALS. (Box-folder 2:104)
    These letters are largely concerned with the settlement of the estate of Francis P. Lee; also include family news.
  - Decree of orphans court, Mobile County [Alabama], March 23, 1850., 2 pages. ADS. (Box-folder 2:105)
    Approves actions of Sarah A. C. Lee as administratrix of Francis P. Lee's estate; household and kitchen furniture, "negro man Isaac," "negro women Sibby and Phobe," were sold in a private sale for an aggregate sum of $2973.31.
  - D. Thompson, Mobile, to S[arah] A. C. Lee, Camden, June 26, 1850., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:106)
    Sends decree of orphans court.
  - Account of administratrix of estate of Francis P. Lee presented in Camden County, New Jersey orphans court, August 7, 1850., 3 pages. ADS. (Box-folder 2:107)
  - Final settlement of estate of Francis P. Lee, Camden County, New Jersey, August 9, 1850., 2 pages. ADS. (Box-folder 2:108)
  - C[harles] C. Gaskell to "cousin" [Sarah A. C. Lee] 1851., 5 items. ALS. (Box-folder 3:1)
    These letters largely concern business matters which Gaskell managed for Lee
  - J[ohn] M. Desaussure acknowledges receipt of money from Sarah A. C. Lee, January 30, 1851., 1 page. ADS. (Box-folder 3:2)
  - Certificate of Ralph V. M. Cooper regarding dealings with Dr. Joseph Fifield, March 22, 1851., 1 page. ADS. (Box-folder 3:3)
  - Account of [Sa]rah Ann C. Lee with A. Bensent Co. ?, Philadelphia, for shares of bank stock, November 1851., 1 page. D. (Box-folder 3:4)
  - C[harles] C. Gaskell to "cousin" Sarah A. C. Lee, 1852., 7 items. ALS. (Box-folder 3:5)
    These letters largely concern business affairs which Gaskell managed for Lee.
  - Clerk's copy of court judgements against Ralph V. M. Cooper in New Jersey, 1837-1845, March 1, 1852., 2 pages. ADS. (Box-folder 3:6)
  - C[harles] C. Gaskell to "cousin" [Sarah A. C. Lee], 1853., 3 items. ALS. (Box-folder 3:7)
  - W. Morris Cooper, Moorestown, to S[arah] A. C. Lee, July 4, 1853., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 3:8)
  - A. Browning, Camden, to Sarah Ann Lee, December 10, 1853., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:9)
    Dr. Fifield will foreclose the mortgage.
  - Charles C. Gaskell to Sarah A. C. Lee, 1854., 8 items. ALS. (Box-folder 3:10)
    These letters are largely concerned with financial matters which Gaskell managed for Lee.
  - A. Browning, Camden, to Sarah Ann Lea [sic], January 7, 1854., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:11)
    Has inquired about the mortgage on the homestead; is acting as counsel for Ralph's children.
  - A. Browning, Camden, to Sarah A. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, January 7, 1854., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:12)
    Asks if she had ever heard Dr. Fifield or Ralph mention use of timber to pay off the homestead mortgage.
  - Charles C. Gaskell to Sarah A. C. Lee, 1855., 7 items. ALS. (Box-folder 3:13)
  - Charles C. Gaskell to Sarah A. C. Lee, 1856., 4 items. ALS. (Box-folder 3:14)
    These letters are largely concerned with financial matters which Gaskell handled for Lee.
  - Charles C. Gaskell to Sarah A. C. Lee, 1857., 9 items. ALS. (Box-folder 3:15)
  - Charles C. Gaskell to Richard W. Howell ,March 3, 1857., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:16)
    Discusses Cooper family legal problems and encloses sketch of the facts of the case.
  - Charles C. Gaskell to Sarah A. C. Lee, 1858., 7 items. ALS. (Box-folder 3:17)
  - C[harles] C. Gaskell to "cousin" [Sarah A. C. Lee], 1859., 3 items. ALS. (Box-folder 3:18)
  - W. B. Kerfoot[?], College of St. James, to S[arah] A. C. Lee, April 11, 1859., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 3:19)
    Will ask the bookkeeper to reexamine accounts; John might do better at school.
  - H. [W. Conner?], New Orleans, to Sarah [A. C. Lee], May [6], 1859., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 3:20)
    Has been busy in land speculation and has bought a farm; sends a check.
  - Memorandum of accounts of S[arah] A[nn] C[ooper] Lee with the [treasurer] of Raritan Township, New Jersey, for land taxes, 1859-1866., 1 page. D. (Box-folder 3:21)
  - C[harles] C. Gaskell to "cousin" [Sarah A. C. Lee], 1860-1861., 9 items. ALS. (Box-folder 3:22)
  - S[arah] A. C. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, to Thomas B. Lee, February 24, 1860., 2 copies. ALS. (Box-folder 3:23)